If you can't imagine
life without chocolate,
you're lucky you weren't born before the 16th century.
Until then, chocolate only existed in Mesoamerica /ˌmesəʊəˈmerɪkə 中美洲/
in a form quite different from what we know.
As far back as 1900 BCE,
the people of that region had learned
to prepare the beans
of the native /ˈneɪtɪv/ cacao /kəˈkɑːəʊ 可可树/ tree.
The earliest records tell us the beans
were ground
and mixed with cornmeal /ˈkɔːnˌmiːl 玉米粉/
and chili /ˈtʃɪlɪ 红辣椒/ peppers /ˈpepə/
to create a drink -
not a relaxing /rɪˈlæksɪŋ/ cup of hot cocoa /ˈkəʊkəʊ/,
but a bitter /ˈbɪtə 苦味/, invigorating /ɪnˈvɪɡəˌreɪt 使精力充沛/ concoction /kənˈkɒkʃən  调制品/
frothing /frɒθ 使起泡沫/ with foam /fəum/.
And if you thought we make
a big deal about chocolate today,
the Mesoamericans /ˌmesəʊəˈmerɪkən 中美洲/ had us beat /biːt/.
They believed that cacao /kəˈkɑːəʊ 可可树/
was a heavenly /ˈhɛvənlɪ 神圣的/ food
gifted to humans
by a feathered serpent /ˈsɜːpənt 蛇/ god,
known to the Maya /ˈmɑˌjɑ/ as Kukulkan
and to the Aztecs as Quetzalcoatl.
Aztecs used cacao /kəˈkɑːəʊ 可可树/ beans as currency /ˈkɜrənsi 货币/
and drank chocolate at royal /ˈrɔɪəl/ feasts /fiːst/,
gave it to soldiers as a reward
for success in battle,
and used it in rituals /ˈrɪtjʊəl 仪式上的/.
The first transatlantic /ˌtrænzətˈlæntɪk 横跨大西洋的/
chocolate encounter /ɪnˈkaʊntə 遭遇/ occurred in 1519
when Hernán Cortés visited
the court of Moctezuma
at Tenochtitlan.
As recorded by Cortés's lieutenant /luːˈtenənt 海军上尉/,
the king had 50 jugs /dʒʌɡ 罐，壶/ of the drink
brought out and poured /pɔː/ into golden cups.
When the colonists /ˈkɒlənɪst 殖民者/  returned with shipments
of the strange new bean,
missionaries' /ˈmɪʃənərɪ 传教士/ salacious /səˈleɪʃəs 淫秽的/ accounts /解释/
of native customs
gave it a reputation as an aphrodisiac /ˌæfrəˈdɪzɪæk 春药/.
At first, its bitter /ˈbɪtə 苦味/ taste made it
suitable as a medicine for ailments /ˈeɪlmənt 小病/,
like upset /ʌpˈsɛt 不适/ stomachs /ˈstʌmək/,
but sweetening it with honey /ˈhʌnɪ/,
sugar, or vanilla /vəˈnɪlə 香草/
quickly made chocolate a popular delicacy /ˈdɛlɪkəsɪ  精致/
in the Spanish court /kɔːt 宫廷/.
And soon, no aristocratic /ˌærɪstəˈkrætɪk 贵族的/ home was
complete without dedicated /ˈdɛdɪˌkeɪtɪd 专用的/ chocolate ware /wɛə  制品，物品/.
The fashionable drink was difficult
and time consuming to produce
on a large scale /skeɪl/.
That involved using plantations /种植园/
and imported slave labor /ˈleɪbə/
in the Caribbean and
on islands off the coast of Africa.
The world of chocolate would change
forever in 1828
with the introduction of the cocoa /ˈkəʊkəʊ/ press
by Coenraad van Houten of Amsterdam.
Van Houten's invention could separate /ˈseprət 分离/
the cocoa's natural fat, or cocoa butter.
This left a powder that could be mixed
into a drinkable solution
or recombined /rikəmˈbaɪn 调配/ with the cocoa butter
to create the solid /ˈsɒlɪd/ chocolate
we know today.
Not long after, a Swiss chocolatier /ˌtʃɒkəˈlætɪə 巧克力制造商/
named Daniel Peter
added powdered milk to the mix,
thus inventing milk chocolate.
By the 20th century /ˈsɛntʃərɪ/, chocolate
was no longer an elite /ɪˈliːt/ luxury /ˈlʌkʃərɪ/
but had become a treat for the public.
Meeting the massive /ˈmæsɪv 大规模/ demand required
more cultivation /ˌkʌltɪˈveɪʃən 栽培/ of cocoa,
which can only grow near the equator /ɪˈkweɪtə 赤道/.
Now, instead of African slaves
being shipped
to South American cocoa plantations,
cocoa production itself would shift
to West Africa
with Cote d'Ivoire providing two-fifths
of the world's cocoa as of 2015.
Yet along with the growth
of the industry,
there have been horrific /həˈrɪfɪk 极其可怕的 / abuses /əˈbjuːz/
of human rights.
Many of the plantations throughout
West Africa,
which supply Western companies,
use slave and child labor,
with an estimation of more than
2 million children affected.
This is a complex problem
that persists /pəˈsɪst 固执/
despite efforts from major chocolate
companies to partner with African nations
to reduce child
and indentured /ɪnˈdɛntʃə 契约/ labor practices /ˈpræktɪs/.
Today, chocolate has established itself
in the rituals /ˈrɪtjʊəl 例行公事/ of our modern culture.
Due to its colonial /kəˈləʊnɪəl 殖民（地）的/ association with
native cultures,
combined /kəmˈbaɪn/ with the power of advertising,
chocolate retains /rɪˈteɪn 保存/ an aura /ˈɔːrə 给人的感觉 特质/
of something sensual /ˈsɛnsjʊəl 激起性欲的/,
decadent /ˈdɛkədənt 堕落的/,
and forbidden.
Yet knowing more about its fascinating /ˈfæsɪˌneɪtɪŋ 迷人的/
and often cruel /ˈkruːəl 残忍的；残酷的/ history,
as well as its production today,
tells us where
these associations originate /əˈrɪdʒɪˌneɪt v 起源/
and what they hide.
So as you unwrap  /ʌnˈræp/
your next bar of chocolate,
take a moment to consider that
not everything about chocolate is sweet.